DENIS COUTO

Senior Engineer and Cloud Architect

+55 11 95043-8225 Brazilian denis.couto@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/deniscouto/ | about.me/docouto







I am a seasoned professional with more than two decades in the field, blending technical expertise with clear communication and leadership skills. Experienced in designing, deploying and technical delivery in small and large enterprise environments while able to translate complex technical concepts for stakeholders.

Skills & Expertise

- Extensive knowledge of Microsoft Stack (onprem and Azure).
- Solid knowledge in automation tools such as PowerShell, Terraform and Ansible.
- Solid knowledge of Linux administration.
- Solid knowledge software delivery processes and tooling. containers, and tools such as Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, Kubernetes.

Certifications

Azure: DevOps ExpertCCA-V: Citrix Certified Associate-VirtualizationAzure: Administrator AssociateCC-VAD-CC: Citrix CVAD Service on Citrix

MCSE: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure Cloud

Professional Experience

Duosystem, São Paulo, Brazil SRE / Cloud Architect

2023 - Present

A member of the Cloud Architecture team, I have been helping the company to solidify their path into Cloud, especially Azure, establishing standards and governance to achieve solid long-term results. To this point, I was able to help with:

- Assess the company's cloud footprint, which led to:
 - Bring costs down about 30%/year by eliminating shadow IT, orphan resources, deprecated resources, establishing common SKU for similar workloads, consolidating workloads in the cloud and back on-prem where required.
- Architect and deploy Cloud Ingress based on Azure Front Door, Azure Application Gateway and WAF
 policies to deliver applications hosted both on Azure and on-prem, which brought in:
 - Increased application reliability.
 - Secure application delivery.
 - Higher performance due to load balancing and caching.
- Consolidate 3rd party app authentication using SSO with Azure Entra ID, which helped with:
 - Ease the onboarding/offboarding process.
 - Secure company's data against data exfiltration.
- Plan and migrate from AWS to Azure, an in-house digital healthcare product. Running on top of Azure Kubernetes and Azure Functions on a Hub&Spoke architecture, which led to:
 - Consolidation of sparse unmanaged microservices under one governed Cloud.
 - Set the standard on how the company orchestrate containers.
 - · Ramping up teams' technical knowledge.
- Led sessions with US based Microsoft Fast Track team, helping our team to get insights and learn best practices to modernize the core company product.
- Write and troubleshoot Azure DevOps Classic/Yaml Pipelines for App and IAC deployments.
- Write and troubleshoot Terraform code targeting Azure.
- Lead the planning and implementation of a multi subscription landing zone for our datacenter migration project.
- Knowledge sharing of new standards and ways of doing Cloud infrastructure through brown bag type sessions, Wiki articles and writing Standard Operating Procedures (SOP).
- Day to day Azure Cloud operations.

Citrix Systems, Dublin, Ireland

Senior Escalation Engineer

2018 - 2022

Working in the EMEA Escalation team, I provided analysis of complex problems in a 24x7 follow the sun support environment.

In-Depth knowledge of *Citrix DaaS* and Citrix Cloud (Azure based), leveraging debugging techniques to manage high severity cases which could be politically or technically challenging.

Day to day used to go by:

- Leveraging a variety of tools to get to the bottom of issues. Tools like Splunk, Azure CLI, Powershell.
- Reading and correlating code on Sourcegraph to customers issues.
- Analysis of memory dump with WinDBG.
- Deep engaging with Product Engineering trough Jira and Slack for further troubleshooting.
- Mentoring and delivering training sessions to Frontline engineers on how to leverage Powershell with Citrix Products.
- Writing public KB articles with workarounds or fixes mapped to future releases.
- Leading the managing and distribution of the load across a pool of senior engineers.

#Citrix #DaaS #Azure #Identity #Engineering #Debugging #Splunk #Powershell

Ergo Group, Dublin, Ireland

Level 3 Support Engineer

2015 - 2018

Working on escalation/BAU tasks for several customers (Aercap, CIE, Goshawk, AerLingus, Dunbia and many others) managing a variety of products and services, such as: Windows Server, Linux, Azure, Office 365, Hyper-V, VMware ESXi, Netscaler, Xenapp and others.

Also worked on a dedicated team for a high value customer going beyond BAU tasks, I had the opportunity to automate a series of tasks through Powershell using functions and modules that helped to:

- Finding details of servers combining data from AD, Solarwinds and VMware.
- Finding and gathering important details of dozens of SQL Server instances.
- Enabling employees to have their pictures synced across different company's tools.
- Wrapping 3rd party DMS APIs for better integration with LOB applications.

For this same customer, I was the go-to person for their CD solution based on *Octopus Deploy*, orchestrating with a 3rd party vendor the deployment and availability of their main application.

#Level3 #Citrix #Virtualization #Azure #Powershell #Octopus #Elastic #Linux #Ansible

DoMore! Soluções em Produtividade, São Paulo, Brazil

2009 - 2015

Senior Microsoft Infrastructure Engineer

- Planning, deploying, and managing medium to large SharePoint farms and applications for companies like Odebrecht, Vale, PWC, Pfizer, Carrefour and others.
- Administering internal and Azure infrastructure running several Microsoft solutions such as Hyper-V, SharePoint (2007,2010, 2013), Office 365, SQL Server, Visual Studio Team Services.
- Engineering engaging on troubleshooting custom applications.

#SharePoint #Engineering #Powershell

Atento Brasil, São Paulo, Brazil

2006 - 2008

Level 3 Server Support Engineer

- Performing 3rd level support to Windows environment with more than 10.000 users and 12 locations nationwide.
- Managing VMware ESXi and Microsoft network products, Exchange Server 2007

#Level3 #Windows #Virtualization

SSI Consultoria, São Paulo, Brazil

2004 - 2006

Server Administrator

- Managing a Windows network environment and SQL Server together with Visual Source Safe.
- Managing Linux (Red Hat) Iptables Firewall, Web Proxy with Squid and reports with SARG.

#SysAdmin #Windows #Linux #Firewall #Proxy

Languages

- Portuguese Native
- English Fluent

Education

Faculdade Eniac, Guarulhos, São Paulo Computer Networking 2002 - 2004